

Henry Jose Requena Molina

Nationality: Venezuelan | (+57) 3208052459 | <u>hrequena14@gmail.com</u> |

Henry Requena | LinkedIn | Barranquilla, Colombia

About me:

In the last 3 years, I have dedicated myself to various applications of Mechatronic Engineering, starting independently as a 3D designer and manufacturing parts through 3D printing. Later, as part of a research seedbed, I became a Senior Researcher with the registration of prototypes and software with the Ministry of Sciences of Colombia. Finally, keeping up with the latest trends in engineering, I have worked as a professional in the application of techniques for IoT, Machine Learning, and Computer Vision.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

2019 - 2024 - Barranguilla, Colombia

MECHATRONIC ENGINEER - Universidad Autónoma del Caribe

WORK EXPERIENCE

December 1, 2022 - Present - Barranquilla, Colombia

Software Developer - Freelance

- · Application of techniques for IoT (Node.Js, Google Cloud Platform, MQTT Protocol, Influxdb, Grafana, Docker).
- · Management of Linux Servers (Centos, Alma, Rocky).
- · Use of NoSQL databases (MongoDB).
- · Object detection with pre-trained models, OpenCV, and OCR application (Tensorflow, Tesseract, YoloV5, YoloV7).
- · Analysis of control systems.
- Development of metrology software for the calibration of gas meters.

January 10, 2021 - Present - Barranquilla, Colombia

3D Design and Manufacturing - Freelance

- · Design of mechanisms and 3D printing for prototyping.
- · Casings for electronic devices.
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ Repair and maintenance of 3D printers.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

June 1, 2022 - Present - Barranquilla, Colombia

Senior Researcher - Universidad Autónoma del Caribe

- · Design and Manufacturing of Functional Devices.
- \cdot (1) Software registration for flexible manufacturing process machines.
- (3) Software registrations for mechatronic devices.
- \cdot (2) Software and Prototype registrations for Computer Vision.
- Presentation at the III International Congress on Technology and Innovation in Engineering and Computing CIITIC 2023.
- \cdot Article registered and awaiting approval for publication in MDPI-Engineering Proceedings.

Languages

Native Language : Spanish Other Language : English

Skills

Python	JavaScript	Google Cloud Platform		Linux Server	OpenCV	Nvidia Jetson Nano
MongoDB	Machine Learning	MQTT		Android Studio	Flask	WSGI
Docker	Grafana	InfluxDB	IoT	Raspberry Pi	Pytorch	Solidworks
Java	TensorFLow	Yolo Models Computer Vision		Pandas	Scikit Learn	